Guide to the Matthew Redinger Papers 1933, 1986-1988
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Matthew Redinger papers
1933, 1986-1988
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 165
Redinger, Matthew
1.0 linear foot
Matthew Redinger was a University of Montana graduate student. The collection contains Redinger's research for his master's thesis The Civilian Conservation Corps as a tool of the National Park Service: The Development of Glacier and Yellowstone National Parks, 1933-1942.
Biographical Note
Matthew Alan Redinger graduated from the University of Montana with a master's degree in history in 1988. His master's thesis was entitled The Civilian Conservation Corps as a tool of the National Park Service: The Development of Glacier and Yellowstone National Parks, 1933-1942. Redinger studied under H. Duane Hampton in the history department. Upon graduation Redinger moved to Seattle to continue his studies at the University of Washington. He completed his Ph.D. in 1993.
The collection contains Redinger's research for his master's thesis The Civilian Conservation Corps as a tool of the National Park Service: The Development of Glacier and Yellowstone National Parks, 1933-1942. Correspondence with former Civilian Conservation Corps members, Civilian Conservation Corps reports, photographs, statistical information on the camps, articles, and an oral history make up the bulk of the collection.
The collection is divided into four series:
Series I: General Correspondence, 9 folders, 1986-1988
Series II: Research Materials, 13 folders, 1933-1987
Series III: Writings, 2 folders, 1933, 1987
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
The collection was in Redinger's possession until donation to the archives.
Gift of Matthew Redinger, 1988 and 1992.
One audiocassette was transferred to the K. Ross Toole Archives Oral History collection during original processing and is designated as OH 272-001.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Graduate students--Montana--Missoula
New Deal, 1933-1939--Montana; Public works--Montana
Glacier National Park (Mont.); Yellowstone National Park
United States. National Park Service; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.)--Montana--Glacier National Park; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.)--Yellowstone National Park; University of Montana--Missoula--Graduate students
Montana; Photographs; Parks and Playgrounds
- General Correspondence, 1986-1988; Series I; 9 folders
  This series consists mainly of correspondence that Redinger conducted with former Civilian Conservation Corps members from Glacier and Yellowstone parks. Redinger also corresponded with Glacier park historian Bill Sharp. In the correspondence, the members of the Civilian Conservation Corps wrote of their experiences within the parks.
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  - 1986 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - January-September, 1987 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - October, 1987 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - November, 1987 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - December, 1987 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - January, 1988 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - February, 1988 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - March-July, 1988 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - undated (Box-folder 1/9)
- Research Materials, 1933-1987, undated; Series II; 13 folders
  The series consists of the materials that Redinger used in his research of the Civilian Conservation Corps camps in Glacier and Yellowstone parks as well as general Civilian Conservation Corps information. The materials used were maps, statistical information, journal articles, an enrollees Civilian Conservation Corps handbook, records, reports, photos, and clippings. The information that Redinger collected is all facsimiles. There are no original manuscripts. The photographs are also copied.
  The series is arranged by topic.
  - Appendix Material, 1933-1942, 1971 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Articles, 1934-1974 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Articles, 1933-1984 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Calendar, undated (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps Handbook, 1933 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Inventory of Records, undated (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps Reports, 1938-1939, 1944, undated (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Classified Structure Field Inventory Reports, revised 1981 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - General Research Materials, 1933-1984 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - General Research Materials, 1933-1942, undated (Box-folder 2/4)
  - General Research Notes, 1933-1942 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - NACCA Journals, 1986-1987, undated (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Copies of Photographs, 1933-1939, undated (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Annual Reports, 1933-1942, undated (Box-folder 2/8)
- Writings, 1933, 1987; Series III; 2 folders
  The series contains an excerpt of a diary written in 1933 by Joseph Mauceri. The other writing is a paper that Redinger wrote for a graduate course at the University of Montana entitled Franklin Delano Roosevelt's Tree Army in the "Land of Shining Mountains." The paper was a precursor to his master's thesis.
  - Franklin Delano Roosevelt's Tree Army in the "Land of the Shining Mountains," Matthew Redinger, 1987 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Joseph Mauceri diary, 1933; Typescript of Mauceri's diary from his CCC experience at Glacier National Park from June-October, 1933. (Box-folder 2/10)